Preliminary Guide to the James Tobin Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
James Tobin papers
1930-2002
MS 1746
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
60.83
(81 boxes)
The papers consist of correspondence, subject files, and writings, primarily documenting the professional career and personal life of James Tobin as an economist and educator.
Tobin, James, 1918-2002
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of James Tobin, 1999; Elizabeth Tobin, 2002, 2004, and 2006. Gift of Roger G. Tobin and Linda M. Blum, 2004; Gift of William C. Brainard, 2005. Gift of Cowles Foundation, 2005.
Conditions Governing Access
Box 17 of the original accession is restricted until January 1, 2024, and Box 19 of the original accession is restricted until January 1, 2074 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
Boxes 13-19 of Accession 2004-M-088 are restricted until January 1, 2045, without the written permission of any one of Tobin's children or William C. Brainard in accordance with the requirements of the donor's deed of gift.
Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
Biographical / Historical
James Tobin, Nobel laureate and long-time professor of economics at Yale University, was born in Champaign, Illinois, in 1918. In 1939, he graduated from Harvard University, where he also obtained his master's degree in 1940 and his Ph.D. in 1947. He worked in the Office of Price Administration and on the Civilian Supply and War Production Board before enlisting in the navy in 1941 and serving as an officer aboard the USS Kearney. Tobin began his career at Yale in 1950 as an associate professor, and went on to become the Sterling Professor of Economics. In 1961, he was asked to serve on the Council of Economic Advisors to President John F. Kennedy. His highly regarded work as a Keynesian macro economist, particularly the development of his "portfolio selection theory," earned him the Nobel Memorial Prize in Economic Science in 1981. Tobin married Elizabeth Fay Ringo in 1946; they had four children: Margaret, Louis, Hugh, and Roger. Tobin died on March 11, 2002, in New Haven.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence, subject files, and writings, primarily documenting the professional career and personal life of James Tobin as an economist and educator.
Economics; Keynesian economics; Nobel Prizes; Tobin, James, 1918-2002; Yale University -- Faculty
- Inventory
  - Correspondence, miscellaneous
    - 1973-1983 (Box 1)
    - 1983-1988 (Box 2)
    - 1987-1993 (Box 3)
    - 1994 Jan-Oct (Box 4)
    - 1994 Nov-Dec (Box 5)
  - Class notes [lecture notes taken by Tobin in undergraduate courses], 1930s, undated (Box 6–7)
  - Teaching files, 1951-1996 (Box 7)
    - 1951-1976 (Box 8)
    - 1975-1980 (Box 9)
    - 1981-1988 (Box 10)
    - 1990-1998, no date (Box 11)
    - Restricted files, 1954-1998 (Box 19)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Material in these teaching files is restricted until January 1, 2074 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
  - Subject files
    - Economists, 1955-1973, undated (Box 12)
    - Health care policy, 1994 (Box 12)
    - South Africa, 1986 (Box 12)
    - Bishop's pastoral letter, 1985-1986, undated (Box 12)
    - Exxon-Valdez, 1991 (Box 12)
    - Tobin's Q ratio, 1987-1993, undated (Box 12)
    - Conference (Little Rock, Arkansas), 1982 (Box 12)
    - Fisher, Irving, 1993-1995, undated (Box 12)
    - Poverty, welfare, Murray, 1983, n.d (Box 13)
    - Leuven Belgium lectures, 1982-1983 (Box 13)
    - China, 1985 (Box 13)
    - McGovern campaign, 1972 (Box 13)
    - Balanced budget amendment, 1980s-1990s (Box 14)
    - "100 economists letter", 1992 (Box 14)
    - Food demand experiment, 1995-1997, undated (Box 14)
    - Puerto Rico, 1975 (Box 14)
    - "Money" book, 1951-1979 (Box 15)
    - Kenya [working papers], 1972-1973 (Box 15)
    - Patinkin, Don, 1981 (Box 15)
    - Growth and development, 1970, undated (Box 15)
    - Arms race, 1993-1995 (Box 15)
    - Economics articles, 1978, undated (Box 15)
    - Science priorities, 1997 (Box 15)
    - Federal Reserve Bank of New York, 1996 (Box 15)
    - Yellen, Janet L., 1989-1997 (Box 15)
    - Magnus, Jan R., 1996 (Box 15)
    - Global economy conference, 1997 (Box 15)
    - Magnus/Morgan experiment, 1978-1986 (Box 15)
    - Marshall Plan, 1997, undated (Box 15)
    - Russian economic policy, 1996-1997, undated (Box 15)
    - Minnesota, 1982 (Box 15)
    - Gorbachev, Mikhail, 1997 (Box 15)
    - Nobel Prize [clippings], 1981 (Box 15)
    - China, 1972 (Box 15)
    - University of California, Berkeley [commencement address], 1983 (Box 15)
    - Commission on inflation and economic welfare, 1969-1970 (Box 16)
    - Speech notes, undated (Box 16)
    - Stein, Jerome, 1977-1978 (Box 16)
    - Reviews of Tobin's writings, 1981, undated (Box 16)
    - Friedman, Milton, 1981, undated (Box 16)
    - Ratner, Jonathan, undated (Box 16)
    - Nobel Prize [articles on], 1967-1978 (Box 16)
    - Economic Times [colloquium], 1990-1996 (Box 16)
    - Memorandum on economic growth, 1960 (Box 16)
    - Currency unions, 1998 (Box 16)
    - Gamble lecture panel, 1998 (Box 16)
    - Alcohol tax, undated (Box 16)
    - Brookings Institution, 1998 (Box 16)
    - National Review, 1993 (Box 16)
    - American Philosophical Society, 1997-1998 (Box 16)
    - Modeling capital inflow, 1987, undated (Box 16)
    - Growth and environment, undated (Box 16)
    - Inflation, 1979, 1988 (Box 16)
    - Money and Income: Post Hoc Ergo Propter Hoc, 1969 (Box 16)
    - Monetarist counter-revolution today, 1980 (Box 16)
    - Janeway lectures, 1974-1978 (Box 16)
    - Monetarism conference, 1975, undated (Box 16)
    - Basic income allowances, 1965, undated (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous, 1960s-1990s (Box 16)
  - Yale University
    Yale University records are restricted until January 1, 2024 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
    - Yale governance, 1971-1995 (Box 17)
    - School of Management crisis, 1989 (Box 17)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Faculty Appointments, 1981 (Box 17)
    - Tuition postponement option, 1970s (Box 17)
    - Brewster, Kingman, 1970s (Box 17)
  - Council of Economic Advisors [duplicates of materials sent to the John F. Kennedy Presidential Library], 1960s (Box 18)
- Additional Material, Accession 2003-M-005
  Scope and Contents
  This accession consists of files taken from Tobin's office shortly after his death. Dates range from the 1930s to the 2000s. The General files include correspondence, printed matter, and other materials relating to Tobin's work as an economist and professor at Yale University. The files are arranged alphabetically. The Writings comprise predominantly unpublished pieces by Tobin.
  - General files
    - Airline ticketing-Conference Board (Box 1)
    - Conference Board-CSFI (Box 2)
    - Dahl, Robert-Eichengreen, Barry (Box 3)
    - Eisner, Robert-Gebauer, Wolfgang (Box 4)
    - Friends of the South Asian Study Committee-Institute for Social Research (Box 5)
    - Institute for Women's Policy Research- Korean Daily (Box 6)
    - Kotz, Hans-Helmut-Massachusetts Institute of Technology (Box 7)
    - Mitsui Lectures- Quarterly Journal of Economics (Box 8)
    - Quality Stabilization Bill-Scherer, Fred (Box 9)
    - Schiff, Frank-Tinbergen, Jan (Box 10)
    - Tobin biographical material-Tobin Tax (Box 11)
    - Tobin Tax-Yale College Steering Committee (Box 12)
    - Yale College Steering Committee-Zoumaras, Thomas (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous topical files (Box 14–15)
  - Subject files, 1995 correspondence, teaching materials (Box 16)
  - Harvard class notes (Box 17–18)
  - Chronological correspondence
    - 1986-1989, 1997-1999 (Box 19)
    - 1995-1996 (Box 20)
  - Topical files including Conference Board on Consumer Price Index, SANWA, Yale Workshop in Quantitative Economic Research, teaching files, personal data, "Kennedy recollections" (Box 21)
  - Tobin Tax (Box 22)
  - Tobin Q ratio (Box 23)
  - Writings
    - A-Economic (Box 24)
    - Economic-Heller (Box 25)
    - House-Memo for the Kennedy Campaign (Box 26)
    - Memorial remarks-On the Federal Budget Deficit (Box 27)
    - Ontario-Yes (Box 28)
- Additional Material, Accession 2004-M-088
  This accession consists of files taken from Tobin's home two years after his death. Dates range from the 1920s to 2001. The files are primarily personal papers and include correspondence, photographs, manuscript materials, and some memorabilia relating to Tobin's personal life as well as his work as an economist and professor at Yale University. The files have been named and arranged in the order in which they arrived. The broadest headings come from labels affixed to boxes by Elizabeth Tobin (James Tobin's niece) when she prepared the papers for transfer.
  Original audiotapes and videotapes in Box 11 and floppy discs in Box 12 are restricted. Researchers should contact the reference archivist to arrange for the creation of use copies of these materials.
  The cache of restricted records are restricted until January 1, 2045. Written permission from one of James Tobin's children or William C. Brainard must be obtained to consult these materials. Researchers should consult with the reference archivist for details.
  - Family history, Jim's pre-1935 letters
    - Letters home from Camp Highlands and other youth related material (Box 1)
    - Grade school (Box 1)
    - High school graduation, 1935 (Box 1)
    - "JT Academic Record" in a folder together with this label [report cards] (Box 1)
    - Parents (Box 1)
    - Materials collected by Jim about his father (Box 1)
    - Louis Michael Tobin insurance, Circa 1920 (Box 1)
    - Margaret A. Tobin's real estate (Box 1)
    - Mother (Box 2)
    - RGT material, Circa 1940 (Box 2)
    - University High [high school writings and ephemera], Circa 1940 (Box 2)
    - Letters from Ireland - family history- 19thcentury [letters, photographs, lock of hair], 1800's (Box 2)
    - M.E.T. property, 1970s (Box 2)
    - University High, Circa 1985 (Box 2)
    - 18th century portraits of James Feliz Tobin (Box 2)
    - Margaret Tobin Lecture Series, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Family history [many clippings] (Box 2)
  - Letters to Jim
    - SAT, 1935 (Box 3)
    - Letters to Jim
      - 1935 (Box 3)
      - 1935-1939 [letters plus Spanish War pin] (Box 3)
      - 1937-1938 (Box 3)
      - 1937-1941 ["some possibly earlier"] (Box 3)
      - 1938-1939 (Box 3)
      - c. 1939-1941 ["1980 copies of Murphy letters of Mis folder given to Murphy"] (Box 3)
      - 1940 (Box 3)
      - 1941 friends and family (Box 3)
      - 1941-1942 from friends (Box 3)
  - Professional correspondence [job offers made to Jim] (Box 4)
  - Nobel Prize related correspondence and other materials
    - American Economic Association, 29 December 1982 (Box 4)
    - Telegram from Nobel Committee, 1981 (Box 4)
    - Nobel congratulations letters, 1981 and after (Box 4)
    - Nobel congratulations letters, 1981 and after (Box 5)
    - Nobel statement by Jim, 1981 (Box 5)
    - Nobel articles, [1981-1983] (Box 5)
  - Personal correspondence, 1990s (Box 5)
  - "MISC for WISC" [includes correspondence with Lawrence Summers and others, notes, and other miscellaneous materials], 1994-1999 (Box 5)
  - Social Security reform speech, 1999 (Box 5)
  - Saving Social Security 62%, 1999 (Box 5)
  - NYE/Guide to Keynes (Box 6)
  - Harvard 55th, 1994 (Box 6)
  - Harvard 6/8/95 [Honorary Degree] (Box 6)
  - About Russian non-visit, 1999 (Box 6)
  - Poetry (Box 6)
  - Autobiographical (Box 6)
  - Poetry 2001 (Box 6)
  - Nobel Prize, Circa 1981
    - Congratulation letters and clippings [multiple folders] (Box 6)
    - Stockholm, Sweden, scheduled events, undated (Box 6)
  - Armistice Day photograph, 1918 (Box 7)
  - Retirement, correspondence, 1988 (Box 7)
  - Kennedy telegram [invitation to JFK funeral], 1963 (Box 7)
    - Dad's clippings [L. M. Tobin clippings file on James] (Box 7)
  - Central Intelligence Agency [Project Charles], 1951-1953 (Box 7)
  - Civil Service, 1940s-1960s (Box 7)
  - U.S. Navy Officer Service Record [includes shoulder board], 1940s-1950s (Box 7)
  - War [four photographs], Circa 1945 (Box 7)
  - Files from Bill Brainard, other work files, speeches, talks, etc.
    - Autobiographical notes (Box 7)
    - Obstfeldt-Taylor draft, 1998 (Box 7)
    - Yale-Brookings Conference Washington, DC [Okun], 1999 November (Box 7)
    - Reprints sent, Circa 1981 (Box 7)
    - Congratulations (Box 7)
    - Nobel Prize (Box 7)
    - Manuscript of a textbook on intellectual development, macroeconomics [unpublished, with Bill Brainard, Gary Smith, and Janet Yellin], 1960s-1970s (Box 8)
    - Early manuscripts and important professional correspondence (Box 8)
    - Guideposts [manuscript, probably for Council of Economic Advisors, with background], undated (Box 9)
    - Negative Income Tax Experiment - adjudication for Watts and Baumel welfare sampling, Circa 1969 (Box 9)
    - Professional correspondence - Harry Johnson, Circa 1966 (Box 9)
    - Survey Research Center - early drafts, 1960s (Box 9)
    - Talks and material for talks, [1960s-1980s] (Box 9)
    - "Committee to Study Puerto Rico's Finances, Report to the Governor", 1975 (Box 9)
    - Unpublished manuscript from the 1940s [on "optimizing behavior," parts written in Switzerland in 1959], 1940s-1950s (Box 9)
    - Teaching, 1990s (Box 9)
  - Unsorted - for archives
    - Fisher Conference Hall Discussion, May 1998 (Box 9)
    - Ellis, Barber, JFK, Circa 1999 (Box 9)
    - Health Policy - Bradley (Box 9)
    - CPI Report - Final (Box 9)
    - Lindbeck Welfare State (Box 9)
    - Fisher/Club (Box 9)
    - "The Tobin Tax: How to Make it Real", 1999 (Box 10)
    - Japan Yoshikawa, 1999-2000 (Box 10)
    - Godley (Box 10)
    - World Bank paper offprints (Box 10)
    - Neoclassical synthesis, Circa 1993 (Box 10)
    - Fisher Symposium, comment on Hall (Box 10)
    - To Wisconsin, miscellaneous (Box 10)
    - Office- Yale, Circa 1999 (Box 10)
    - W. Godley (Box 10)
    - [Loose papers] (Box 10)
  - Videocassettes
    Audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
    - "James Tobin and California Economy", 1993 February 16; 1 (Box 20)
    - "JEC: James Tobin, Paul Samuelson, George Perry, L. Kudlow testimony", 1992 February; 1 (Box 21)
    - "JEC: Professors Tobin, Solow, Meltzer", 1993 February 11; 1 (Box 22)
    - "First Annual Pacific-Basin Finance Conference", undated; 1 (Box 23)
    - "U.S.S. Kearney DD432", 1992 October 15
      - Original videocassette (Box 11)
      - Duplicating master (Box 11-D)
      - Use copy (Box 11U)
  - Audiocassettes
    Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
    - "Broadcast of May 4, 1995 Side 1" [2 copies], 2 (Box 24–25)
    - "Lecture at KDI", 1989 March 23; 1 (Box 26)
  - Computer diskettes [3.5 inch]
    Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
    - HP SL Drivers Disk 1 of 3 [removed for preservation; consult reference archivist], 2004-M-088.0001 (Box 12)
    - HP SL Drivers Disk 2 of 3 [removed for preservation; consult reference archivist], 2004-M-088.0002 (Box 12)
    - HP SL Drivers Disk 3 of 3 [removed for preservation; consult reference archivist], 2004-M-088.0003 (Box 12)
    - fpapers5-2; helsink1; tunn2; clinton.nks; clinton2; cbo1192; ecseccnl [removed for preservation; consult reference archivist], Circa 1992; 2004-M-088.0004 (Box 12)
    - Kennedy.wpd 10-17-97; WP6.1 Tobin; QDATA Backup 7-5-99 [removed for preservation; consult reference archivist], 1997, 1999; 2004-M-088.0005 (Box 12)
    - \amphlsoc; \bonn [removed for preservation; consult reference archivist], 2004-M-088.0006 (Box 12)
    - Tobin2 [removed for preservation; consult reference archivist], 2004-M-088.0007 (Box 12)
    - June 22 95; selected c:\123wk c:\tspwk; Stevens Feb 96; 123wk6*.* [lectures?] [removed for preservation; consult reference archivist], 1995-1996; 2004-M-088.0008 (Box 12)
    - Tobin's Q and Serkan's work, all Lotus [removed for preservation; consult reference archivist], 2004-M-088.0009 (Box 12)
    - Serkan Savasoglu; File Disk as in c:\office; general; rec; misc; manuscr; ch2 app. new 10/23; tinberg [removed for preservation; consult reference archivist], 2004-M-088.0010 (Box 12)
    - 2 note files [removed for preservation; consult reference archivist], 2004-M-088.0011 (Box 12)
    - 7/87 from JT office; \office selected files; Fshrdrft [removed for preservation; consult reference archivist], 1987; 2004-M-088.0012 (Box 12)
    - 10/21/99; publist.wrk; telephon [removed for preservation; consult reference archivist], 2004-M-088.0013 (Box 12)
    - Bio; Manuscr; Publist; Telephon; General; Misc; Rec [removed for preservation; consult reference archivist], 2004-M-088.0014 (Box 12)
    - General; Manuscript; Misc; Publist; Rec; Telephon Fishtxt.197 [removed for preservation; consult reference archivist], 2004-M-088.0015 (Box 12)
    - Tobin 9-97; General; Misc.; Publist2.new; Rec; wagner.ins; Manuscr; Q; Telephon.97 [removed for preservation; consult reference archivist], 2004-M-088.0016 (Box 12)
    - publist publistwrkg } deleted by mistake [removed for preservation; consult reference archivist], 2004-M-088.0017 (Box 12)
    - publist.wpd - clean list; publistwkg.wpd - working list w/ corrections [removed for preservation; consult reference archivist], 2004-M-088.0018 (Box 12)
    - 1998 WPD files; Hansen et al [removed for preservation; consult reference archivist], 2004-M-088.0019 (Box 12)
    - Bushtax.abs [removed for preservation; consult reference archivist], 2004-M-088.0020 (Box 12)
    - \letters summer 94 CLEAN; JEC 794 [removed for preservation; consult reference archivist], 2004-M-088.0021 (Box 12)
    - Summer 95 letters for office; \radright [removed for preservation; consult reference archivist], 2004-M-088.0022 (Box 12)
    - Summer 97 for Wisco; From F:\; From: \office [removed for preservation; consult reference archivist], 2004-M-088.0023 (Box 12)
    - Papers 6; opeds [removed for preservation; consult reference archivist], 2004-M-088.0024 (Box 12)
    - Amphlsoc.fnl; worldbnk.wpd final; worldbnk5.fnl, 2004-M-088.0025 (Box 12)
    - Bill Parker - remarks at retirement, May 1989 - JT [removed for preservation; consult reference archivist], 2004-M-088.0026 (Box 12)
    - JTvolEE - new volume of Tobin essays [removed for preservation; consult reference archivist], 2004-M-088.0027 (Box 12)
  - Restricted papers
    These records are restricted until January 1, 2045. Written permission from one of James Tobin's children or William C. Brainard must be obtained to consult these materials. Researchers should consult with the reference archivist for details.
    - Family History
      Boxes 13-19 of Accession 2004-M-088 are restricted until January 1, 2045, without the written permission of any one of Tobin's children or William C. Brainard due to the requirements of the donor's deed of gift.
      - Roget Anketell Homestead, 1901 (Box 13)
      - Correspondence with family, Circa 1948 (Box 13)
      - "Pearl harbor and After" Autobiographical Note with floppy (Box 13)
      - "Harvard in the 1930s." Autobiographical Note. (Box 13)
      - "Navy 42" Autobiographical Note. (Box 13)
      - Jim's children artwork, in his office in 2000 (Box 13)
      - 40th Wedding Anniversary Celebration (Box 13)
      - Family photos (1922) and official history deaths of Jim's great grandparents (Box 13)
      - Passports (Box 13)
      - Anketell and Tobin history - found in a file together (Box 13)
      - "St. Luke's Story" Autobiographical fragment (Box 13)
      - Springbrook history photos - labeled by MET (Box 13)
      - From a file labelled "Letters to keep" (Box 13)
      - Family history materials sent to Jim from Louis Anketell's descendents in Nampa, Idaho [photographs and postcards], Circa 1900s (Box 13)
      - Birth, marriage, passport documents (Box 13)
    - Harvard undergraduate years
      - Letters home from Harvard undergraduate years, 1930s-1940s (Box 14)
      - Harvard awards (Box 14)
      - Unsorted [contains clippings and photographs], 1930s-1940s (Box 14)
      - Official (Box 14)
    - Letters from Jim from Europe 1939 and from Harvard graduate school 1939-1941
      - Letters from Europe trip, 1939 (Box 15)
      - Letters from Harvard, 1939-1941 (Box 15)
      - Jim's letters to Harvard friends, 1940-1943 (Box 15)
      - Letters, War years (Box 15)
    - Letters from Jim - Navy years
      - Letters home while in Navy (Box 15)
      - Letters from Navy (Box 16)
      - Letters home, 1944-1946 (Box 16)
      - Navy citation, 1947 (Box 16)
      - Navy - in a folder together, 1950s (Box 16)
      - G.I. Bill - Veterans Administration (Box 16)
      - U.S.S. Kearny, 1993-1994 (Box 16)
      - U.S.S. Kearny - history and photographs, 1940s (Box 16)
      - Letters - War years, 1939-1945 (Box 16)
    - Letters from Jim and Betty 1949; letters to Jim 1941-1945; letters from Jim in Washington 1941-1942
      - Letters home from Washington, 1941 (Box 17)
      - Letters home from England, 1949 (Box 17)
      - Letters from Jim to Betty, 1949 (Box 17)
      - Letters to Jim, Circa 1941-1945 (Box 17)
      - Letters Worth Keeping (Box 17)
    - 1950s and 1960s
      - Correspondence with friends, 1950s-1960s (Box 17)
      - Clark medal, 1950s (Box 17)
      - Professional correspondence, 1960s (Box 17)
      - Negotiations with Cowles Foundation, 1954 (Box 17)
      - Family correspondence, 1950s-1960s (Box 17)
      - Purchase of Springbrook Red Barn, 1955 (Box 17)
      - Negotiations with Harvard, 1957 (Box 17)
      - Springbrook Upkeep, 1960s (Box 17)
    - 1970s
      - Family Correspondence from Nairobi, Kenya, 1972-1973 (Box 18)
      - Professional Correspondence and papers, 1970s (Box 18)
      - Family Correspondence, 1970s (Box 18)
      - Correspondence, 1970s (Box 18)
      - Baseball game created by Jim, Circa 1960s (Box 18)
    - Clippings, photographs, 1980s- 1990s
      - Safire (Box 18)
      - Clippings (Box 18)
      - Photographs (Box 19)
      - Magic Mountain (Box 19)
      - Political Interests (Box 19)
      - Economics in daily life (Box 19)
      - General Admiration (Box 19)
      - Betty's health (Box 19)
      - Miscellaneous papers at time of his death (Box 19)
      - Professional Correspondence, 1980s-2001 (Box 19)
      - Family Correspondence, 1980s-1990s (Box 19)
      - Correspondence, 1980s, 2001 (Box 19)
      - Work in progress, 2001 (Box 19)
      - Dick Finn (Box 19)
- Additional Material, Accession 2005-M-006
  - Letter to Linda Blum re: tenure decision at the University of Michigan, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Yale University. Local 34 strike in 1984